[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
overview and different approaches of
tosca parameters
also explain the approach of test
configuration parameters
the explanation will be done through
demonstration
the test case which was developed in
last tutorial we have provided the test
data directly as a hard-coded value
the main disadvantage of this approach
is whenever we need to change the data
we need to update the test case
so to avoid this we need to go for
parameterization
[Music]
tosca allows different approaches to
perform parameterization
the basic approaches are
buffer which is similar to variables
which holds values during the execution
test configuration parameters this is
another way to parameterize the test
data
the test configuration parameters can be
created in test case folder or execution
list level
business parameters which are used to
parameterize the reusable test step
blocks
we will discuss about this while
creating libraries in tosca
apart from this tosca also provide
advanced features such as test case
design test data management test data
services etc to handle complex test data
now i will explain the concepts of test
configuration parameter in short tcp
the tcp can be created in test case
folder or execution list level
if the test configuration parameters are
defined in parent folder level same
parameter values can be retrieved from
subfolder and all the test cases
available under that parent folder
the test configuration parameters are
read only during execution
so it has to be defined before the
execution
[Music]
the syntax to read tcp parameter is the
cp parameter name
the tcps are visible in the test
configuration section of every test case
folder or execution list
ideally we should use the test
configuration parameters for the common
or configuration related data which are
applicable for throughout the test
suites
the examples of the tcp are application
path or url credential environment
details reporting path etc
provides default test configuration
parameters as well that are used to
customize test configurations
for an example if we want to execute the
test case in the chrome browser we need
to add tcp as browser with value chrome
now we will create test configuration
parameter in test case level
select the test case and click on test
configuration tab
right click on test name and click on
option create test configuration in
violet colored button
provide a proper name to the newly
created parameter
we use the name as my tcp
[Music]
now we can assign any value to this new
test configuration parameter
we will assign the value of this tcp to
the existing test step for creation of
buffer
we use the syntax cp my tcp as the
buffer value
during the execution the value of tcp
12345 will be assigned to
buffermybuffer1
execute the test case in scratchbook to
check the tcp parameter value assignment
[Music]
scratchbook log shows that tcp value
assigned to buffer correctly
the new value of buffermybuffer1 can be
checked from bufferviewer as well
similarly we can create the tcp and
folder level and execution list level as
well
if we create it in folder level then the
tcp can be accessed from all the test
cases which are created under same
folder
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca parameters and
test configuration parameter
we will learn more about tosca library
reusable test step block and business
parameters to manage test data in next
video
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query